<method>
	<name>
		AdaBoost algorithm with C4.5 Decision Tree as Base Classifier
	</name>
	<reference>  
		<ref>
			Y. Freund and R. E. Schapire. A decision-theoretic generalization of on-line learning and an application to boosting, Journal of Computer and System Sciences, vol. 55, no. 1, pp. 119-139, 1997.
		</ref>
	</reference>
	<generalDescription>  
		<type>
			Ensemble of classifiers. Boosting.
		</type>
		<objective>
			To determine a set of decision trees that on the basis of answers to questions about the input attributes predicts correctly the value of the target attribute.
		</objective>
		<howWork>
			AdaBoost uses the whole data-set to train each classifier serially, but after each round, it gives more focus to difficult instances, with the goal of correctly classifying examples in the next iteration which were incorrectly classified during the current iteration. Hence, it gives more focus to examples that are harder to classify, the quantity of focus is measured by a weight, which initially is equal for all instances. After each iteration, the weights of misclassified instances are increased; on the contrary, the weights of correctly classified instances are decreased. Furthermore, another weight is assigned to each individual classifier depending on its overall accuracy which is then used in test phase; more confidence is given to more accurate classifiers. Finally, when a new instance is submitted, each classifier gives a weighted vote, and the class label is selected by majority.
        </howWork>
		<parameterSpec>  
			<param>
				prune: wether to prune or not prune the tree. It is a boolean value that determines if the algorithm applies a prune process after building the tree
			</param>
			<param>
				confidence: is the confidence level. It is a float value that determines what is the minimal confidence that must has a leaf in order to can be considered in the tree
			</param>
			<param>
				minItemsets: is the minimum number of item-sets per leaf. It is an integer value that determines how much data instances must contain a leaf in order to can be created
			</param>
			<param>
				Number of Classifiers: is the maximum number of iterations that the boosting procedure will be executed
			</param>
			<param>
				Train Method: is the method used to train the classifier in each iteration (using resampling or cost-sensitive classifier)
			</param>
		</parameterSpec>
		<properties>
			<continuous>Yes</continuous>
			<discretized>Yes</discretized>
			<integer>Yes</integer>
			<nominal>Yes</nominal>
			<valueLess>Yes</valueLess>
			<impreciseValue>No</impreciseValue>
		</properties>
	</generalDescription>
<example>
Problem type: Imbalanced
Method: AdaBoost algorithm with C4.5 Decision Tree as Base Classifier
Dataset: abalone9-18
Training set: abalone9-18-5-5-1tra.dat
Test set: abalone9-18-5-5-1tst.dat
Test Show results: TSTImb-AdaBoost
Parameters: default values

After the execution of RunKeel.jar we can see the classification results for the test set:

G-mean in Training: 1.0
F-mean in Training: 1.0
TPrate in Training: 1.0
G-mean in Test: 0.46969342795496954
F-mean in Test: 0.3333333333333333
TPrate in Test: 0.2222222222222222
Accuracy in training: 1.0
Accuracy in test: 0.9455782312925171

We can also see the output and target classes for each case of the test set (result0.tst) in Experiment\Results\Imb-AdaBoost.abalone9-18:

@relation  abalone9-18
@attribute Sex{M,F,I}
@attribute Length real[0.075,0.815]
@attribute Diameter real[0.055,0.65]
@attribute Height real[0.0,1.13]
@attribute Whole_weight real[0.0020,2.8255]
@attribute Shucked_weight real[0.0010,1.488]
@attribute Viscera_weight real[5.0E-4,0.76]
@attribute Shell_weight real[0.0015,1.005]
@attribute Rings{positive,negative}
@inputs Sex,Length,Diameter,Height,Whole_weight,Shucked_weight,Viscera_weight,Shell_weight
@outputs Rings
@data
negative negative
negative negative
negative negative
negative negative
negative negative
positive negative
negative negative
negative negative
negative negative
negative negative
positive positive
negative negative
negative negative
positive negative
positive negative
positive negative
negative negative
negative negative
negative negative
negative negative
negative negative
negative negative
negative negative
negative negative
negative negative
negative negative
negative negative
negative negative
negative negative
negative negative
...
</example>

</method>
