<method>

	<name>Alcalaetal</name>

	<reference>  

		<ref>Alcala-Fdez, J., Alcala, R., Gacto, M.J., Herrera, F. Learning the membership function contexts for mining fuzzy association rules by using genetic algorithms. ScienceDirect, Fuzzy Sets and Systems 160(2009) 905-921</ref>

	</reference>

	<generalDescription>  

		<type>Association Rules Mining by means of Genetic-Fuzzy Learning Methods</type>

		<objective>Alcala-Fdez et all proposes a fuzzy data-mining algorithm for extracting both association rules and membership functions from quantitative transactions.</objective>

		<howWork>Based on the 2-tuples linguistic representation model,Alcala-Fdez et all proposes a new fuzzy data mining algorithm for
extracting both fuzzy association rules and membership functions from quantitative transactions by means of a genetic learning of the
MFs and the use of a basic method for mining the fuzzy association rules.In this way,the search space reduction provided by the 2-tuples
linguistic representation helps the genetic search technique to obtain more suitable MFs. Moreover,this way to work allow learn the
most adequate context for each fuzzy partition,which is necessary in different contextual situations with the aim of getting high 
quality fuzzy association rules.</howWork>

		<parameterSpec>  
			
			<param>Number of Evaluations: The maximum number of evaluations to accomplish before terminating the genetic learning.</param>
			<param>Population Size: The maximum size of population to handle after each generation.</param>
			<param>Number of Bits per Gene: The number of bit digits for encoding a displacement within a gene.</param>
			<param>Decreasing Factor of L threshold (NOT USED): It represents the value used for decreasing the "L" threshold.</param>
			<param>Factor for Parent Centric BLX Crossover: It indicates the value for controlling the Parent Centric BLX crossover.</param>
			<param>Number of Fuzzy Regions for Numeric Attributes: The number of fuzzy regions with which numeric attributes are evaluated.</param>
			<param>Use Max Operator for 1-Frequent Itemsets: It indicates whether the max operator must be used while discovering 1-Frequent Itemsets.</param>
			<param>Minimum Support: The user-specified minimum support for the mined association rules.</param>
			<param>Minimum Confidence: The user-specified minimum confidence for the mined association rules.</param>
		
		</parameterSpec>

		<properties>

			<continuous>Yes</continuous>

			<discretized>Yes</discretized>

			<integer>Yes</integer>

			<nominal>Yes</nominal>

			<valueLess>No</valueLess>

			<impreciseValue>No</impreciseValue>

		</properties>

	</generalDescription>

	<example>
Problem type: Association Rules
Method: Alcalaetal
Dataset: weather
Parameters: default values


After the execution of RunKeel.jar we can see XML representations of the mined association rules along with the values concerning the measures of interest, respectively, in:

&quot;results/Asso-Alcalaetal.weather/result0s0.tra&quot;

&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;rules&gt;
&lt;rule id="0"&gt;
&lt;antecedents&gt;
&lt;attribute name="outlook" value="overcast"/&gt;
&lt;/antecedents&gt;
&lt;consequents&gt;
&lt;attribute name="play" value="yes"/&gt;
&lt;/consequents&gt;
&lt;/rule&gt;
&lt;/rules&gt;


&quot;results/Asso-Alcalaetal.weather/result0s0.tst&quot;


&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;values n_one_frequent_itemsets=&quot;12&quot; n_rules=&quot;52&quot;&gt;
&lt;rule id=&quot;0&quot; rule_support=&quot;0.2857142857142857&quot; antecedent_support=&quot;0.2857142857142857&quot; confidence=&quot;1.0&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/values&gt;


We can also see some relevant information on-screen:


Reading the transaction set: ../datasets/weather/weather.dat
Opening the file: ../datasets/weather/weather.dat.
 Processing inputs and outputs
 The number of output attributes is: 1


  Reading the data 
  Number of instances read: 14

  Finishing the statistics: (isTrain)true, (# out attributes)1
  File LOADED CORRECTLY!!

Pass: 1; Total Frequent Itemsets: 12
Pass: 2; Total Frequent Itemsets: 38; Total Association Rules: 3
Pass: 3; Total Frequent Itemsets: 42; Total Association Rules: 9
Pass: 4; Total Frequent Itemsets: 42; Total Association Rules: 9

Number of Frequent Itemsets found: 42
Number of Association Rules generated: 9
Average Support: 0.26190476190476186
Average Confidence: 0.9841269841269842
Average Antecedents Length: 1.6666666666666667
Number of Covered Records (%): 92.85714285714286

Algorithm Finished

0.096 seconds


</example>

</method>
