<method>

	<name>Data Mining for Evolutionary Learning </name>

	<reference>

		<ref>W.H. Au, K.C.C. Chan, X. Yao. A novel evolutionary data mining algorithm with applications to churn prediction. IEEE Transactions on Evolutionary Computation 7:6 (2003) 532-545.</ref>

	</reference>

	<generalDescription>

		<type>Classification model by Genetic Rule induction</type>

		<objective>To determine a set of rules that predicts correctly the value of the target attribute</objective>

		<howWork>DMEL searches through the possible rule space using an evolutionary approach
that has the following characteristics: 1) the evolutionary
process begins with the generation of an initial set of first-order
rules (i.e., rules with one conjunct/condition) using a probabilistic
induction technique and based on these rules, rules of higher order
(two or more conjuncts) are obtained iteratively; 2) when identifying
interesting rules, an objective interestingness measure is
used; 3) the fitness of a chromosome is defined in terms of the
probability that the attribute values of a record can be correctly
determined using the rules it encodes; and 4) the likelihood of predictions
(or classifications) made are estimated so that subscribers
can be ranked according to their likelihood to churn.
		</howWork>

		<parameterSpec>

			<param>Population size: Total number of individuals in the population</param>
			<param>Probability_choice_crossover_operator: Probability of application of the crossover operator</param>
			<param>Mutation_probability: Probability of application of the mutation operator</param>
			<param>Number_generations: Maximum number of iterations allowed</param>

		</parameterSpec>

		<properties>

			<continuous>Yes</continuous>
			<discretized>Yes</discretized>
			<integer>Yes</integer>
			<nominal>Yes</nominal>
			<valueLess>Yes</valueLess>

			<impreciseValue>No</impreciseValue>

		</properties>

	</generalDescription>

	<example>Problem type: Classification
Method: DMEL
Dataset: wisconsin
Training set: wisconsin.dat
Test set: wisconsin.dat
Test Show results: Vis-Clas-Check
Parameters: default values

After the execution of RunKeel.jar we can see into the experiment\results\Vis-Clas-Check folder the classification results for the test and train set:

TEST RESULTS
============
Classifier=
Fold 0 : CORRECT=0.9692532942898975 N/C=0.0
Global Classification Error + N/C:
0.03074670571010249
stddev Global Classification Error + N/C:
0.0
Correctly classified:
0.9692532942898975
Global N/C:
0.0

TRAIN RESULTS
============
Classifier=
Summary of data, Classifiers:
Fold 0 : CORRECT=0.9692532942898975 N/C=0.0
Global Classification Error + N/C:
0.03074670571010249
stddev Global Classification Error + N/C:
0.0
Correctly classified:
0.9692532942898975
Global N/C:
0.0

</example>

</method>
