<method>

	<name>GeneticFuzzyAprioriMS</name>

	<reference>  

		<ref>Chen, C.-H., Hong,T.-P., Tseng, V.S., Lee C.-S. A genetic-fuzzy mining approach for items with multiple minimum supports. Soft Computing, Springer-Verlag (2008)</ref>

	</reference>

	<generalDescription>  

		<type>Association Rules Mining by means of Genetic-Fuzzy Learning Methods</type>

		<objective>The fuzzy, the genetic and the clustering concepts are used together to discover useful fuzzy association rules, suitable minimum support values and membership functions from quantitative transactions.</objective>

		<howWork> The proposed framework maintains a population of sets of minimum support values and membership functions, and uses the 
genetic algorithm to automatically derive the resulting one. It first uses the k-means clustering approach to gather similar items into groups. 
All items in the same cluster are considered to have similar characteristics and are assigned similar values when a population is initialized.
The values (or initialization information) include an appropriate number of linguistic terms for each item, its reasonable membership functions,
and a range of its possible minimum support values. It then generates and encodes each set of minimum support values and membership functions 
into a fixed-length string according to the initialization information. Each chromosome is then evaluated by the requirement satisfaction and 
the suitability of membership functions to estimate its fitness value. The evaluation results are utilized to choose appropriate chromosomes
for mating. The offspring sets of membership functions and minimum support values then undergo recursive evolution until a good set 
(the highest fitness value) has been obtained. Finally, the derived minimum support values and membership functions are used to mine fuzzy
association rules by the approach in Lee et al. (2004).</howWork>

		<parameterSpec>  
			
			<param>Number of Evaluations: The maximum number of evaluations to accomplish before terminating the genetic learning.</param>
			<param>Population Size: The maximum size of population to handle after each generation.</param>
			<param>Probability of Mutation: The probability of the mutation operator.</param>
			<param>Probability of Crossover: The probability of the crossover operator.</param>
			<param>Parameter d for MMA Crossover: The parameter which is used while executing the Max-Min-Arithmetical crossover operator.</param>
			<param>Use Max Operator for 1-Frequent Itemsets: It indicates whether the max operator must be used while discovering 1-Frequent Itemsets.</param>
			<param>Maximum Minimum Support: The user-specified maximum minimum support to generate minimum supports for each item (it will be considered if it is different from -1.0).</param>
			<param>Minimum Confidence: The user-specified minimum confidence for the mined association rules.</param>
			<param>Number of clusters: A parameter k for k-means clustering in order to divide the items into clusters.</param>
			<param>Interval Threshold: A threshold to remove intervals.</param>
			<param>Break Threshold:  A threshold to get the cluster break points</param>
			<param>Percentage of the required number of large 1-itemsets: The percentage of the required number of large 1-itemsets.</param>
		
		</parameterSpec>

		<properties>

			<continuous>Yes</continuous>

			<discretized>Yes</discretized>

			<integer>Yes</integer>

			<nominal>Yes</nominal>

			<valueLess>No</valueLess>

			<impreciseValue>No</impreciseValue>

		</properties>

	</generalDescription>

	<example>
Problem type: Association Rules
Method: GeneticFuzzyAprioriMS
Dataset: weather
Parameters: default values


After the execution of RunKeel.jar we can see XML representations of the mined association rules along with the values concerning the measures of interest, respectively, in:

&quot;results/Asso-GeneticFu.weather/result0s0.tra&quot;

&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;rules&gt;
&lt;rule id="0"&gt;
&lt;antecedents&gt;
&lt;attribute name="temperature" value="cool"/&gt;
&lt;/antecedents&gt;
&lt;consequents&gt;
&lt;attribute name="humidity" value="normal"/&gt;
&lt;/consequents&gt;
&lt;/rule&gt;
&lt;/rules&gt;


&quot;results/Asso-GeneticFu.weather/result0s0.tst&quot;


&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;values n_one_frequent_itemsets=&quot;12&quot; n_rules=&quot;52&quot;&gt;
&lt;rule id=&quot;0&quot; rule_support=&quot;0.2857142857142857&quot; antecedent_support=&quot;0.2857142857142857&quot; confidence=&quot;1.0&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/values&gt;


We can also see some relevant information on-screen:


Reading the transaction set: ../datasets/weather/weather.dat
Opening the file: ../datasets/weather/weather.dat.
 Processing inputs and outputs
 The number of output attributes is: 1


 Reading the data 
 Number of instances read: 14

  Finishing the statistics: (isTrain)true, (# out attributes)1
  File LOADED CORRECTLY!!

Pass: 1; Total Frequent Itemsets: 12
Pass: 2; Total Frequent Itemsets: 33; Total Association Rules: 2
Pass: 3; Total Frequent Itemsets: 42; Total Association Rules: 8
Pass: 4; Total Frequent Itemsets: 42; Total Association Rules: 8

Number of Frequent Itemsets found: 42
Number of Association Rules generated: 8
Average Support: 0.22321428571428564
Average Confidence: 0.9821428571428572
Average Antecedents Length: 1.75
Number of Covered Records (%): 64.28571428571429

Algorithm Finished

0.55 seconds

</example>

</method>
