<method>

	<name>Friedman Test and Post-Hoc Procedures</name>

	<reference>  

	<ref>D. Sheskin, Handbook of parametric and nonparametric statistical procedures. Chapman and Hall/CRC, 2003. </ref>

	</reference>

	<generalDescription>  

		<type>Application of non-parametric tests.</type>

		<objective>Execution of the non-parametric Friedman test and post-hoc tests for comparison of the global performance of several classification methods.</objective>

		<howWork>
		Friedman test is a non-parametric equivalent of the test of repeated-measures ANOVA. It computes the ranking of the observed results for algorithm 
		for each data-set, assigning to the best of them the ranking 1, and to the worst the ranking k. We may apply different post-hoc test in order to detect
		significant differences between the algorithms. Specifically we may choose among Iman and Davenport test, Bonferroni-Dunn test, Holm test, Hochbergh test,
		Hommel test, Holland test, Rom test, Finner test or Li test.
		</howWork>

		<parameterSpec>  
		<param>Apply-Iman-Davenport: It can takes the value YES or NO if the user desires to apply the Iman and Davenport test</param>
		<param>Apply-Bonferroni-Dunn: It can takes the value YES or NO if the user desires to apply the Bonferroni-Dunn test</param>
		<param>Apply-Holm: It can takes the value YES or NO if the user desires to apply the Holm test</param>
		<param>Apply-Hochberg: It can takes the value YES or NO if the user desires to apply the Hochberg test</param>
		<param>Apply-Hommel: It can takes the value YES or NO if the user desires to apply the Hommel test</param>
		<param>Apply-Holland: It can takes the value YES or NO if the user desires to apply the Holland test</param>
		<param>Apply-Rom: It can takes the value YES or NO if the user desires to apply the Rom test</param>
		<param>Apply-Finner: It can takes the value YES or NO if the user desires to apply the Finner test</param>
		<param>Apply-Li: It can takes the value YES or NO if the user desires to apply the Li test</param>
			<param>imbalancedMeasure: The measure used in the method, one of the measures used imbalanced classification area</param>
		</parameterSpec>

		<properties>
		</properties>

	</generalDescription>

	<example>Problem type: Classification 
Methods to compare: Clas-SMO vs Clas-KNN vs Clas-C45
Datasets: glass1, haberman, pima, wisconsin
Default Parameters (all the post-hoc tests are applied)
Type of partitions: k-fold, k=5

After the execution of RunKeel.jar we can see into the ./results/Stat-Imb-Friedman/TSTClas-SMOvsClas-KNNvsClas-C45 folder the results0s0.stat file:

------------------------------------------------------------
Friedman Test, Imbalanced Classification
Area Under the ROC Curve in each fold:
Algorithm = Clas-SMO
Fold 0 : 0.5
Fold 1 : 0.5
Fold 2 : 0.5
Fold 3 : 0.5
Fold 4 : 0.5
Mean Value: 0.5
Algorithm = Clas-KNN
Fold 0 : 0.6759259259259259
Fold 1 : 0.7976190476190476
Fold 2 : 0.7619047619047619
Fold 3 : 0.8642857142857143
Fold 4 : 0.8444444444444444
Mean Value: 0.7888359788359789
Algorithm = Clas-C45
Fold 0 : 0.7002314814814815
Fold 1 : 0.7285714285714286
Fold 2 : 0.7333333333333334
Fold 3 : 0.7928571428571429
Fold 4 : 0.7444444444444445
Mean Value: 0.7398875661375662
--------------------------------------------------------------

and a LaTeX output file "output.tex" where the results of the application of the test is provided.

</example>

</method>
