<method>

	<name>CHC Adaptative Search for Instance Selection</name>

	<reference>  

		<ref>J.R. Cano, F. Herrera, M. Lozano. Using evolutionary algorithms as instance selection for data reduction in KDD: An experimental study. IEEE Transaction on Evolutionary Computation 7:6 (2003) 561-575</ref>

	</reference>

	<generalDescription>  

		<type>Preprocess Method. Data Reduction. Instance Selection. Evolutionary</type>

		<objective>Reduce the size of the training set without losing precision or accuracy in order to a posterior classification</objective>

		<howWork>CHC evolutionary algorithm applied to the Instance Selection Problem. During each generation the CHC develops the following steps.
		1. It uses a parent population of size N to generate an intermediate population of N individuals, which are randomly paired and used to generate N potential offsprings.
		2. Then, a survival competition is held where the best N chromosomes from
		the parent and offspring populations are selected to form the next generation.
		CHC also implements a form of heterogeneous recombination using HUX,
		a special recombination operator. HUX exchanges half of the bits that differ
		between parents, where the bit position to be exchanged is randomly determined. CHC also employs a method of incest prevention. Before applying HUX
		to two parents, the Hamming distance between them is measured. Only those
		parents who differ from each other by some number of bits (mating threshold)
		are mated. The initial threshold is set at L=4, where L is the length od the
		chromosomes. If no offspring are inserted into the new population then the
		threshold is reduced by one.
		No mutation is applied during the recombination phase. Instead, when the
		population converges or the search stops making progress, the population is
		reinitialized to introduce new diversity to the search. The chromosome representing the best solution found over the course of the search is used as a template to reseed the population. Reseeding of the population is accomplished by randomly changing 35 percent of the bits in the template chromosome to form each of the other N - 1 new chromosomes in the population. The search is the resumed.</howWork>

		<parameterSpec>  
			<param>Population Size: Integer value. Number of chromosome belonging to the population.</param>
			<param>Number of Evaluations: Integer value. Maximal number of evaluations allowed in the run of the algorithm</param>
			<param>Alfa Equilibrate Factor: Real value. Trade-off factor that controls the balaning between reduction and accuracy</param>
			<param>Percentage of Change in Restart: Real value. Quantity of gens changed in a restart operation</param>
			<param>0 to 1 Probalitity in Recombination: Real value. Probability associated to a restriction in changes from 0 to 1 in recombination operator</param>
			<param>0 to 1 Probability in Diverge: Real value. Probabiliy associated to a restriction in changes from 0 to 1 in diverge operation</param>
			<param>Number of neighbors: Integer value. Number of nearest instances considered to classify an example using the K-Nearest Neighbor Rule</param>
			<param>Distance Function: K-NN implements two distance functions. a) Euclidean with normalized attributed and b) HVDM (see paper D.R. Wilson, T.R. Martinez. Reduction Tecniques For Instance-Based Learning Algorithms. Machine Learning 38:3 (2000) 257-286.)</param>			</parameterSpec>

		<properties>

			<continuous>Yes</continuous>

			<discretized>Yes</discretized>

			<integer>Yes</integer>

			<nominal>Yes</nominal>

			<valueLess>No</valueLess>

			<impreciseValue>No</impreciseValue>

		</properties>

	</generalDescription>

	<example>Problem type: Classification 
Method: IS-CHC
Dataset: iris
Training set: iris-10-1tra.dat
Parameters: default values

We can see output set in Experiment\Results\IS-CHC:

@relation iris
@attribute sepalLength real [4.3, 7.9]
@attribute sepalWidth real [2.0, 4.4]
@attribute petalLength real [1.0, 6.9]
@attribute petalWidth real [0.1, 2.5]
@attribute class {Iris-setosa, Iris-versicolor, Iris-virginica}
@data
5.4,3.4,1.7,0.2,Iris-setosa
5.9,3.0,4.2,1.5,Iris-versicolor
6.1,2.8,4.0,1.3,Iris-versicolor
5.8,2.7,5.1,1.9,Iris-virginica
5.7,2.5,5.0,2.0,Iris-virginica
</example>

</method>