<method>

	<name>Data Complexity Metrics calculation</name>

	<reference>  

	<ref> T.K. Ho and M. Basu. Complexity measures of supervised classification problems, IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence, 24(3) pp. 289-300, 2002.</ref>

	</reference>

	<generalDescription>  

		<type>Estimation of the inherent complexity of the data for the classification task</type>

		<objective>Calculate twelve indicators of the source of complexity for the considered data set</objective>

		<howWork>Twelve measures are computed over the TRAINING data, which provide a hint about the complexity of the data,
i.e the problematics that this data set would pose for the classification task. These measures are of three different types:
- Measures of overlaps in feature values from different classes: F1, F2, F3
- Measures of separability of classes: L1, L2, N1, N2, N3
- Measures of geometry, topology and density of manifolds: L3, N4, T1, T2	
	</howWork>

		<parameterSpec>  
			<param>seed: seed to be used for the random number generator</param>
			<param>runF1: whether to run the F1 measure or not</param>
			<param>runF2: whether to run the F2 measure or not</param>
			<param>runF3: whether to run the F3 measure or not</param>
			<param>runN1: whether to run the N1 measure or not</param>
			<param>runN2: whether to run the N2 measure or not</param>
			<param>runN3: whether to run the N3 measure or not</param>
			<param>runN4: whether to run the N4 measure or not</param>
			<param>runL1: whether to run the L1 measure or not</param>
			<param>runL2: whether to run the L2 measure or not</param>
			<param>runL3: whether to run the L3 measure or not</param>
			<param>runT1: whether to run the T1 measure or not</param>
			<param>runT2: whether to run the T2 measure or not</param>
		</parameterSpec>

		<properties>
			<continuous>Yes</continuous>

			<discretized>Yes</discretized>

			<integer>Yes</integer>

			<nominal>Yes</nominal>

			<valueLess>No</valueLess>

			<impreciseValue>No</impreciseValue>

		</properties>

	</generalDescription>

	<example>
Problem type: Classification 
Method: Data Complexity Metrics
Dataset: Iris
Parameters: default values

Input data:
Training set: iris10-1tra.dat
Test set: iris10-1tst.dat


Output data: DC-Metrics.iris-10-1tra.dat


 F1: 29.048368043421046
 F2: 0.00974192748463432
 F3: 0.5925925925925926
 N1: 0.08888888888888889
 N2: 0.2099144718010419
 N3: 0.0444444444444444
 N4: 0.01666666666666672
 L1: -1.0
 L2: -1.0
 L3: -1.0
 T1: 0.8814814814814815
 T2: 33.75

</example>

</method>