<method>

	<name>MODENAR</name>

	<reference>  

		<ref>B. Alatas, E. Akin and A Karci. MODENAR: Multi-objective differential evolution algorithm for mining numeric association rules. Applied Soft Computing, 8:646–656 (2008).</ref>

	</reference>

	<generalDescription>  

		<type>Association Rules Mining by means of Genetic Algorithms</type>

		<objective>Alatas et al propose a multi-objective differential evolution algorithm for mining numeric association rules</objective>

		<howWork>The genetic learning is performed iteratively until a maximum number of evaluations is reached. 
First an initial population is randomly generated and the rounding operator is applied to the ﬁrst part of decision variables.
All dominated solutions are removed from the population. 
The remaining non-dominated solutions are retained in order to apply the mutation, rounding and repairing operators.
Then, crossover is performed. If the number of non-dominated solutions exceeds some threshold, ﬁltrating operator is applied to remove the parents which are very close to each others. 
Three parents are randomly selected. A child is generated from the three parents and replaced into the population, if it dominates the ﬁrst selected parent; 
otherwise is selected the solution calculated weighted sum ﬁtness of which is bigger. This process continues until the population is completed.
Finally, the adjust of the intervals for the chosen individuals has been performed and is returned the set of non-dominated solutions.
</howWork>	
		<parameterSpec>  
			<param>Population Size: the population size to handle after each generation.</param>
			<param>Number of Evaluations: the maximum number of evaluations to accomplish.</param>
			<param>Crossover rate (CR): the crossover constant to create an offspring from a parent individual and a mutated individual.</param>
			<param>Threshold for the number of non-dominated solutions: the maximum number of non-dominated solutions in the population</param>
			<param>The factor of amplitude for each attribute of the dataset: the amplitude factor related to each attribute of the database.</param>
            <param>Weight for Support: the factor for tuning the importance of the rule support.</param>
			<param>Weight for Confidence: the factor for tuning the importance of the rule confidence.</param>
			<param>Weight for Comprehensibility: the factor for tuning the importance of the number of involved attributes.</param>
			<param>Weight for Amplitude of the Intervals: the factor for tuning the importance of the intervals amplitude.</param>
			
		</parameterSpec>

		<properties>

			<continuous>Yes</continuous>

			<discretized>Yes</discretized>

			<integer>Yes</integer>

			<nominal>Yes</nominal>

			<valueLess>No</valueLess>

			<impreciseValue>No</impreciseValue>

		</properties>

	</generalDescription>

	<example>
Problem type: Association Rules
Method: MODENAR
Dataset: basketball
Parameters: default values (seed = 1286082570)


After the execution of RunKeel.jar we can see XML representations of the mined association rules along with the values concerning the measures of interest, respectively, in:


&quot;results/Asso-MODENAR.basketball/result0s0.tra&quot;

&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;rules&gt;
&lt;rule id=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;antecedents&gt;
&lt;attribute name=&quot;points_per_minuteReal&quot; value=&quot;[0.23472065279598514, 0.653745254730633]&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/antecedents&gt;
&lt;consequents&gt;
&lt;attribute name=&quot;heightInteger&quot; value=&quot;[182.0, 200.0]&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/consequents&gt;
&lt;/rule&gt;
... ... ... ...
&lt;/rules&gt;


&quot;results/Asso-MODENAR.basketball/result0s0.tst&quot;


&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;values&gt;
&lt;rule id=&quot;0&quot; rule_support=&quot;0.85&quot; antecedent_support=&quot;0.97&quot; consequent_support=&quot;0.88&quot; confidence=&quot;0.88&quot; lift=&quot;1&quot; conviction=&quot;0.97&quot; certainFactor=&quot;-0.01&quot; netConf=&quot;-0.13&quot; yulesQ=&quot;-1&quot; nAttributes=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
... ... ... ...
&lt;/values&gt;

Number of Association Rules generated: 57
Average Support: 0.25
Average Confidence: 0.84
Average Lift: 3.72
Average Conviction: Infinity
Average Certain Factor:"0.43
Average Netconf:"0.28
Average YulesQ:"0.38
Average Number of Antecedents: 2.41
Number of Covered Records (%): 95.84

&quot;results/Asso-MODENAR.basketball/result0s0e0.tst&quot;


&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;values&gt;
Support	antecedent_support	consequent_support	Confidence	Lift	Conv	CF	NetConf	YulesQ	nAttributes
0.85  	      0.97	                 0.88	          0.88	        1	0.97  -0.01      -0.13	 -1	   2
... ... ... ...
&lt;/values&gt;

We can also see some relevant information on-screen:


Initialization
Generation: 1
Generation: 2
... ... ... ...
Generation: 187

Number of Association Rules generated: 57
Average Support: 0.25
Average Confidence: 0.84
Average Lift: 3.72
Average Conviction: Infinity
Average Certain Factor: 0.43
Average Netconf: 0.28
Average YulesQ: 0.38
Average Number of Antecedents: 2.41
Number of Covered Records (%): 95.84

Algorithm Finished

</example>

</method>
