<method>

	<name>MOPNAR</name>

	<reference>  

		<ref>D. Martín, A. Rosete, J. Alcalá-Fdez and F. Herrera. A New Multi-Objective Evolutionary Algorithm for Mining a Reduced Set of Interesting Positive and Negative Quantitative Association Rules. IEEE Transaction on Evolutionary Computation, 18:1, 54-69 (2014).</ref>

	</reference>

	<generalDescription>  

		<type>Association Rules Mining by means of Genetic Algorithms</type>

		<objective>The multi-objective evolutionary algorithm proposed by Martin et al. is conceived for mine a reduced set of positive and negative 
quatitative association rules that are interesting, easy to understand and with a good trade-off between the number of rules, support and coverage of the dataset.</objective>

		<howWork>The genetic learning is performed iteratively until a maximum number of evaluations is reached. 
First, the evolutionary model of MOEA/D-DE generates a weight vector or each subproblem and a neighborhood is selected for each weight vector.
Then, the algorithm generates an initial population, initializes the reference point and initializes the external population (EP) with the nondominated rules of the initial population. 
Later, two offspring are generated by crossover, mutation and repairing from a solution of the population and another is selected at random from its neighborhood or from
the population. These offspring are used to update the reference points and replace some of the solutions of the current population with worse values for the decomposition approach.
Finally, the restarting process is applied at the end of each generation when the number of new subproblems in the population is less than difference threshold.
Then, the EP is returned.
</howWork>
		<parameterSpec>  
			
		    <param>Number of Objetives: the number of objectives to optimize</param>
			<param>Number of Evaluations: the maximum number of evaluations to accomplish.</param>
			<param>H control parameter: the integer number to control the population size and weight vectors.</param>
			<param>Weight vectors in neighborhood: the number of weight vectors in the neighborhood of each weight vector </param>
			<param>Probability parent solutions are selected from the neighborhood: the probability that parent solutions are selected from the neighborhood </param>
			<param>Max solutions replaced by each child solution: the maximal number of solutions replaced by each child solution </param>
			<param>Probability of Mutation: the probability of mutation.</param>	
	        <param>The factor of amplitude for each attribute of the dataset: the amplitude factor related to each attribute of the database.</param>
            <param>Difference threshold: the difference between the current population and previous population for which the population is restarted.</param>	

				
		</parameterSpec>

		<properties>

			<continuous>Yes</continuous>

			<discretized>Yes</discretized>

			<integer>Yes</integer>

			<nominal>Yes</nominal>

			<valueLess>No</valueLess>

			<impreciseValue>No</impreciseValue>

		</properties>

	</generalDescription>

	<example>
Problem type: Association Rules
Method: MOPNAR
Dataset: basketball
Parameters: default values (seed = 1286082570)


After the execution of RunKeel.jar we can see XML representations of the mined association rules along with the values concerning the measures of interest, respectively, in:


&quot;results/Asso-MOPNAR.basketball/result0s0.tra&quot;


&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;rules&gt;
&lt;rule id=&quot;0&quot;&gt;
&lt;antecedents&gt;
&lt;attribute name=&quot;points_per_minuteReal&quot; value=&quot;[0.3498, 0.3498]&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/antecedents&gt;
&lt;consequents&gt;
&lt;attribute name=&quot;time_playedReal&quot; value=&quot;[22.87, 22.87]&quot;/&gt;
&lt;/consequents&gt;
&lt;/rule&gt;
&lt;/rules&gt;


&quot;results/Asso-MOPNAR.basketball/result0s0.tst&quot;


&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;values&gt;
&lt;rule id=&quot;0&quot; rule_support=&quot;0.02&quot; antecedent_support=&quot;0.02&quot; consequent_support=&quot;0.02&quot; confidence=&quot;1&quot; lift=&quot;96&quot; conviction=&quot;Infinity&quot; certainFactor=&quot;1&quot; netConf=&quot;1&quot; yulesQ=&quot;1&quot; nAttributes=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;
... ... ... ...
&lt;/values&gt;


Number of Association Rules generated: 93
Average Support: 0.15
Average Confidence: 0.96
Average Lift: 50.68
Average Conviction: Infinity
Average Certain Factor: 0.93
Average Netconf: 0.8
Average YulesQ: 0.98
Average Number of Antecedents: 2.35
Number of Covered Records (%): 98.96

&quot;results/Asso-MOPNAR.basketball/result0s0e0.tst&quot;

&lt;?xml version=&quot;1.0&quot; encoding=&quot;UTF-8&quot;?&gt;
&lt;values&gt;
Support	antecedent_support	consequent_support	Confidence	Lift	Conv	CF	NetConf	YulesQ	nAttributes
0.02  	      0.02	                 0.02	          1	        96  Infinity     1       1	  1	    2
... ... ... ...
&lt;/values&gt;

We can also see some relevant information on-screen:


Initialization
Computing Generation 1
Computing Generation 2
... ... ... ...
Computing Generation 224
done.


Number of Association Rules generated: 93
Average Support: 0.15
Average Confidence: 0.96
Average Lift: 50.68
Average Conviction: Infinity
Average Certain Factor: 0.93
Average Netconf: 0.8
Average YulesQ: 0.98
Average Number of Antecedents: 2.35
Number of Covered Records (%): 98.96

Algorithm Finished

0.807 seconds

</example>

</method>
