<method>

	<name>Genetic-Based New Fuzzy Reasoning Model</name>

	<reference>  

		<ref>D. Park, A. Kandel. Genetic-Based New Fuzzy Reasoning Model with Application to Fuzzy Control, 
		IEEE Transactions on Systems, Man and Cybernetics 24:1 (1994) 39-47</ref>
		
	</reference>

	<generalDescription>  

		<type>Genetic Fuzzy Rule Learning</type>

		<objective>A Genetic Algorithm is used to supplement the fuzzy 
		reasoning model, by means of a fuzzy relation matrix, and to tune 
		the membership functions of the input variables.</objective>

		<howWork>Given a Mamdani Fuzzy Rule Set obtained by a Fuzzy Rule Base System this method searches
		for the best set of parameters for the fuzzy reasoning model in order to achieve the lower 
		mean square error (MSE). It also includes a tuning of the fuzzy membership functions for the
		input variables.
			The NFRM algorithm can be described as follows.
				1) Determine the linguistic descriptions of the input 
				variable X and the output variable Y, and their membership functions.
				2) For a given real-valued input X = x , determine the
					membership degree corresponding to each linguistic description
					of X by means of the fuzzy membership functions.
				3) Determine the fuzzy relation matrix R between the
					linguistic descriptions of X and Y. These relations are
					based on the expert&apos;s knowledge which is given in terms
				of linguistic descriptions.
				4) Calculate the vector y in terms of the vector x and the fuzzy 
				relation matrix R: y = x o R.
			5 ) Using the moment method, transform the vector
			y to the corresponding real number y in the universe of the variable Y.
			
		The genetic process is a simple genetic algorithm, with tournament selection, one-point crossover,
		mutation that changes the value either a 90% or a 110% of the current value, and a generational
		approach with elitism.
		</howWork>

		<parameterSpec>  

			<param>Population Size: Is the number of chromosomes.</param>
			<param>Number Generations: Is the number of generations of the GA</param>
			<param>Cross Probability: Is the probability to apply the one-point crossover.  It is a float value between 0 and 1.</param>
			<param>Mutation Probability: Is the probability to apply the mutation. It is a float value between 0 and 1.</param>

		</parameterSpec>

		<properties>

			<continuous>Yes</continuous>

			<discretized>Yes (only with numerical)</discretized>

			<integer>Yes</integer>

			<nominal>No</nominal>

			<valueLess>Yes</valueLess>

			<impreciseValue>No</impreciseValue>

		</properties>

	</generalDescription>

	<example>Problem type: Regression
        Method: Post-GB-NFRM
        Dataset: ele1
        Training set: daily-electric-energy-10-1tra.dat
        Test set: daily-electric-energy-10-1tst.dat
        Test Show results: Vis-Regr-Check
        Parameters: default values

        After the execution of RunKeel.jar we can see into the experiment\results\Vis-Regr-Check folder the regression results for the test set:

TEST RESULTS
============
Model = 
MSE of all folds:
Fold 0 : 0.267066729407457 
...
Global MSE:
0.2562332521719627 
Global stdev:
0.054408132425051395 
TRAIN RESULTS
============
Model = 
MSE of all folds:
Fold 0 : 0.21341088549869108 
...
Global MSE:
0.2284557180225128 
Global stdev:
0.024018105205013452

		We can also see the output data base and rule base in Experiment\Results\Post-GB-NFRM\Regr-Fuzzy-WM.

</example>

</method>