<method>

	<name>Statistical two Normal samples variance comparation F test</name>

	<reference>  

<ref>Snedecor, G. W., Cochran, W. G.: Statistical Methods. Iowa State University Press, Ames, IA. (1989)</ref>


	</reference>

	<generalDescription>  

		<type>Statistical two sample means comparation using the  F test by mean of Stat-Regr-SnedecorF algorithm.</type>

		<objective>Execution of StatTestModF test for comparing two regression methods performance.</objective>

		<howWork>
Stat-Regr-SnedecorF is a method for comparing the performance of two regression algorithms using statistics techniques. It can be used in k-folds and 5x2 cross validation training  experiments.
Stat-Regr-SnedecorF is associated to the training and testing results of the two models in an experiment that are to be compared. Once those models has been trained and tested, the Stat-Regr-SnedecorF takes place. 
The process calculates the mean cuadratic error for each partitions results. The statistical sample includes all of those error measures for each method to be compared. Then the F-Test is executed with the Null hypothesis as true if both methods have equals variance.
</howWork>

		<parameterSpec>  
<param>signlevel: a value in the range (0,1). Default value:  0.95. The significance level represents the probability of erroneous rejecting the NULL Hypothesis.</param>
		</parameterSpec>

		<properties>
		</properties>

	</generalDescription>

	<example>Problem type: Regression 
Methods to compare: Regr-LinearLMS vs Regr-PolQuadraticLMS
Dataset: machine-cpu
Type of partitions: k-fold, k=10

After the execution of RunKeel.jar we can see into the ./results/Stat-Regr-SnedecorF/TSTRegr-LinearLMSvsRegr-PolQuadraticLMS/ folder the results0s0.stat file:

F test, Modeling
Mean cuadratic error in each fold:
Algorithm = 0
Fold 0 : 6269.340047889225 
Fold 1 : 2147.2024593503747 
Fold 2 : 1995.8867100647303 
Fold 3 : 8429.461050092124 
Fold 4 : 3752.8946186462886 
Fold 5 : 1265.75194457092 
Fold 6 : 1378.2443444675362 
Fold 7 : 10369.871521593977 
Fold 8 : 13447.477062000205 
Fold 9 : 3784.308766572497 
Algorithm = 1
Fold 0 : 19883.17406264338 
Fold 1 : 923.086212825497 
Fold 2 : 1782.6768777295042 
Fold 3 : 40347.29384309221 
Fold 4 : 2902.9903279394525 
Fold 5 : 1706.9056645604135 
Fold 6 : 445.70708214385405 
Fold 7 : 4560.977759698817 
Fold 8 : 5227.39838633173 
Fold 9 : 1143.2328230123044 
Null hypothesis, equal variances
Output=0: There is evidence against H0
p-value:
0.0029132565237861563</example>

</method>
