<method>

	<name>Relief-F</name>

	<reference>  

		<ref>Igor Kononenko. Estimating Attributes: Analysis and Extensions of RELIEF. European Conference on Machine Learning, 171-182, 1994</ref>

	</reference>

	<generalDescription>  

		<type>Non Evolutionary Filter method</type>

		<objective>Feature Selection. This method allows search to follow feature subsets</objective>

		<howWork>Relief-F selects features that are statistically relevant. Therefore, nearest neighbours (one instance per each class) are sought for each given instance (I), one is near-hit (H), and the others are near-misses (J).
Ideally, a feature is relevant if each value are the same between I and near-hit, and different between I and near-mis.
The relevant feature are those having theirs weight exceeding a relevant threshold (relevanceThreshold). This relevanceThreshold can be determine by a statistical method of interval estimation. The sample size numInstancesSampled can be varied and a large number numInstancesSampled implies more reliable approximation.
		</howWork>

		<parameterSpec>  
			<param>paramKNN: is the number of nearest neighbours used by the k-NN classifier</param>
			<param>relevanceThreshold is a final threshold that selects the features (its weights must improve this value)</param>
			<param>numInstancesSampled is the number of instances that the method needs</param>
			
		</parameterSpec>

		<properties>

			<continuous>No</continuous>

			<discretized>Yes</discretized>

			<integer>Yes</integer>

			<nominal>Yes</nominal>

			<valueLess>No</valueLess>

			<impreciseValue>No</impreciseValue>

		</properties>

	</generalDescription>

	<example>

Problem type: Preprocess
Method: Relief-F
Dataset: Car
Training set: car-10-1tra.dat
Test set: car-10-1tst.dat
Parameters: default values


After the execution of RunKeel.jar we can see the training and test datasets modified only with the selected features.

And the extra file with the classification error in test validation result0e0.txt:

result0e0.txt

RESULTS generated at Fri Jul 02 19:44:58 CEST 2010 
--------------------------------------------------
Algorithm Name: Relief-F

PARTITION Filename: ../datasets/car/car-10-1tra.dat
---------------

Features selected: 
Persons - Lug_boot - Safety - 

3 features of 6

Error in test (using train for prediction): 0.30057803468208094
Error in test (using test for prediction): 0.2774566473988439
---------------


</example>

</method>